<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantum Computing on Stefano Giannini</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/physics/quantum_computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantum Computing on Stefano Giannini</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/physics/quantum_computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Quantum Computing - Fundamentals - Teleportation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/physics/quantum_computing/teleportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/physics/quantum_computing/teleportation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Quantum teleportation is a fundamental protocol in quantum information science that enables the transfer of quantum information from one location to another. Despite its name, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve the transportation of matter, but rather the transmission of the quantum state of a particle.
The Concept In quantum teleportation, we have three main parties:
Alice: The sender who wants to transmit a quantum state. Bob: The receiver who will receive the quantum state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing - Fundamentals (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/physics/quantum_computing/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/physics/quantum_computing/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Quantum Computing Quantum computing represents a transformative leap in computational technology. Unlike classical computers, which use bits as the smallest unit of data, quantum computers employ quantum bits, or qubits. These qubits take advantage of the principles of quantum mechanics, allowing for exponentially greater processing power in certain types of computations.
Core Concepts:
Superposition: Unlike classical bits that can be either 0 or 1, qubits can exist in a state that is a superposition of both.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
